Julius Morgan Clements papers, 1888-1921
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Julius Morgan Clements papers, 1888-1921
AZ 419
The collection includes correspondence, reports, financial records, maps, and photographs relating to mining activities in the American West and Sonora, Mex., and to his tenure as an American Trade Commissioner, U.S. Dept. of Commerce, in Japan and China.
Clements, Julius Morgan, b. 1869
1.2 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Julius M. Clements was a mining engineer with interests in Arizona and around the country. He served as an American Trade Commissioner for the U.S. Dept. of Commerce in Japan and China.
Organization
This collection is organized into three series:
Series I: Personal Material and Correspondence, 1888-1919
Series II: South America and Far East Material, 1904-1921
Series III: Mining Material, 1902-1915
Scope and Content Note
The collection includes correspondence, reports, financial records, maps, and photographs relating to mining activities in the American West and Sonora, Mex., and to his tenure as an American Trade Commissioner, U.S. Dept. of Commerce, in Japan and China. Includes some personal correspondence, clippings about family members, and photographs of South America, the Far East, and mining in the Western United States.
Access Terms
Clements, Julius Morgan, b. 1869
Cameron, Ralph H. (Ralph Henry), b. 1863
Mines and mineral resources -- West (U.S.) -- History -- Sources
Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona -- History -- Sources
Mines and mineral resources -- Mexico -- Sonora (State) -- History -- Sources
Japan -- Description and travel
China -- Description and travel
East Asia -- Description and travel
Correspondence
Reports
Photographs
Blueprints
Separated Material
Some photographs received with this collection were removed and cataloged separately.
Container List
- Series I: Personal Material and Correspondence, 1888-1919
  - Biographical material. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Family correspondence, clippings, etc. 1888-1919 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Brother, Frank Clements, regarding their mother's estate. 1905-1911 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and clippings regarding his second wife, Josephine. 1908-1911 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Marthe Libert. 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Financial Records: Trust Companies. 1903-1911 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Financial Records: Miscellaneous. 1907-1910 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Mining Correspondence. 1902-1918 (Box 1, Folder 8-10)
  - Correspondence: Ralph H. Cameron, regarding the Grand Canyon Power Project. 1909-1910 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series II: South America and Far East Material, 1904-1921
  - South America: Photographs, articles by Julius M. Clements, notes. 1904 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Far East: Correspondence. 1917-1921 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Far East: Photographs, diary. 1920 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - British War Office Map of China. 1913 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Showing railways, telegraphs and treaty ports.
  - U. S. Department of Commerce, Bureau of Foreign & Domestic Commerce, Map of China. November 1918 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Showing the transportation development problem in Peking.
  - Far East: Reports from Japan. 1917-1920 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Far East: Articles by Julius M. Clements. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Far East: Kailau Mining Administration. 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Far East: Miscellaneous Material. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Series III: Mining Material, 1902-1915
  - Arizona: Keystone Copper Company report and blueprints, Gila County. 1908 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Arizona: Oriental Mining Company report, Yavapai County. No date (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Arizona: French Gulch report, near Kirkland. 1910 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Arizona: London-Arizona Copper Company report, Gila County. 1907 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Arizona: Hobson Group report, Yavapai County. 1906 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Arizona: Copper Blossom Group report, Yavapai County. 1906 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Arizona: Temporal Group report, Santa Cruz County. 1906 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Arizona: Troy-Manhattan Copper Company report, Pinal County. 1907 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Mexico: San Antonio Copper Company annual report, maps, etc., Sonora. 1908-1909 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Mexico: San Antonio Copper Company topographic blueprints, Sonora. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Mexico: Promontoria Mine report. 1909 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Mexico: Republica del Sur Mines report. No date (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Mexico: San Lorenzo Mine report. 1909 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Mexico: Cananea Mining District report. 1902 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Alaska: Kotsina Copper Company report, map, etc., Kotsina District, Copper River Region. 1907 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Colorado: Gold King Consolidated Mines Company (including Gold Prince Mine) reports, notes, etc. 1906-1915 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Montana: Golden Curry Mines blueprints and photo. 1905, 1910 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Montana: Silver King and Plymouth Mines blueprints of underground works. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - New Mexico: Mangas Development Company reports, maps, blueprints, etc., Burro Mountain Mining District, Grant County. 1906-1910 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - New Mexico: Mangas Development Company cost sheets, record of churn drill, Burro Mountain Mining District, Grant County. 1909-1910 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - New Mexico: Germany Mining and Development Company blueprints, correspondence, etc., Kelly, N. M. 1910 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Alabama: Stickney & Company report, Birmingham District. 1902 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - California: Dubb's Property report, Cocopah Mountains. 1912 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - California: Butte and Nance Group report and map, San Bernardino County. No date (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Colorado: Buffalo Boy and Old Abe Groups report, San Juan District. 1915 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Nevada: Mayflower and Maybelle Groups report, Red Butte, Jackson Mountains, Humboldt County. No date (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Montana: Butte Continental Copper Company report and correspondence, Butte, Silver Bow County. 1907 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Notes on mining costs for various companies. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Mine Development Company Agreement, Magdalena Mining District, Socorro County, New Mexico. 1907 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Goldfield Mining and Milling Company Lease, Superstition Mining District, Maricopa and Pinal Counties, Arizona. 1908 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Mistake Mine Affidavit of Labor Performed, etc., Globe Mining District, Gila County. No date. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Three-R-Group of Mining Claims, blue prints, Santa Cruz County, Arizona. 1911 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Colorado Mining photographs. 1915 (Box 3, Folder 9)